This video is sponsored by Firecore, one
of the best open-source solution to
power your AI application with clean
data from any website. Last week, I got
a lot of good feedback on breaking down
a PRD into smaller tasks. And today, I
want to share two more really important
tips and workflow that help you
dramatically reduce huge amount of
errors for bigger and complex projects
with cursor. One is called taskdriven
development. Another is setting up
memory bank for your cursor project.
With those two flow, I was able to get
cursor implement complex function and
making sure the code generated
integrated into existing codebase very
well. I will show you my best practice
workflow so you can adopt it for your
own project. So first thing I want to
talk about is taskdriven development.
Sometimes you might want cursor to build
some sort of complex function that it
won't get it right at first try. And for
this type of scenario often you will
encounter arrow then you paste this
arrow to cursor tell it to update code
and fix it. But then you might got more
errors after you try different fix and
you will just kind of be the messenger
between the testing result and cursor
for multiple different times until it
kind of works. But still while it is
iterating that specific function, it
often will break something else. And
this is very common and super
frustrating. And what I found really
useful is this concept of testdriven
development that basically means a
software development process where you
define and write the test for your
functions or features before you write a
code to implement those features. For
example, you can define a test script
where you can define expect input for
the function you're going to write and
expect output validate and you will
write just enough code to pass a test
and improve the code while ensuring all
the tests still pass where it will tell
you if the test passed or not so that
you can iterate a function based on the
test result. On one hand, help you align
the requirement of what expect input and
output with cursor but most importantly
because cursor can run the command line
to run the test by itself. Then you can
just turn on the yolo mode and ask it to
write a test, write a function, run a
test and iterate a function multiple
times until all the tests pass. I will
show you a quick example. But before I
dive into that, I know many of you are
building AI applications or AI agents
that need to access certain website data
from research about business to get the
latest news and a smart and reliable way
to turn any website data into large
language model friendly format is
critical. That's why I want to introduce
you to Fore. If you don't know if I cro
there was first open source project that
offer an effective way to turn any
website into clean format that is
optimized for large language model to
consume. You can browse through all the
subpages of a website and they handle
PDF, word doc or excel file that
attached from URL and also has
capability like smartwe so you can guess
your website with more strict anti-bos
setup and what's really cool is that
they just had a launch week where a
whole bunch of feature has been
introduced that make web scraping 10x
ether for example they introduced this
extract endpoint where it can handle
pageionation and page interactions. So
if you want to script e-commerce website
where you need to click through multiple
different page to get full content, you
can use the endpoint very easily and get
structured product information out. And
my personal favorite is this fire one
web action agent. They went beyond just
scraping a specific website by building
intelligent agent that can navigate
through a specific domain to uncover
niche data that you want. For example, I
can give the URL just prompt it about
the information I care about. This agent
will open up a browser, navigate through
the website to multiple different pages
until you found a page that contains the
information and can also handle scenario
that require logging as well. You can
just simply give a prompt and you'll be
able to take those complex actions and
extract structured data out. Most
importantly, those ability can be called
val API directly. So you can just write
a simple script like this to have a
research agent on demand available
anytime or automation with zapier
make.com and many others by calling file
crawl API directly. So if you're looking
for a smarter way to script internet
data, I highly recommend you go check
out firecro. Now let me show you an
example of how to use this testdriven
development process. So I want cursor to
build a solution for me that where I can
paste in such JSON like string which
including pact model as well as nested
JSON stream and have very easy way to
just view this JSON type string. There
are existing JSON viewer tool already
where you can paste in those type of
string. It will allow you to quickly
view the JSON structure like this. But
it generally didn't work when you mix
together with pandetic model as well as
nested JSON stream. So I wanted
something better and I tried multiple
times with latest coding model but it
almost always fail because it's actually
pretty complex. So this is a great
example. It is a complex function. Very
likely it won't get it right at
beginning but by defining test cases
clearly you can put a cursor in the
driver seat and let it iterate until the
function is ready. So I will open the
cursor chat and give the prompt create a
function that convert JSON like string
into the proper readable JSON. Firstly
let's write some tests then implement
the code then run test and iterate code
until all tests pass. So with this one
it should already start writing some
tests. But in this case I'll also try to
include a example input output so it
understand what I want better. So I can
paste in this example inputs as well as
example output that I expected to
deliver. Then I can click send. And
while we're doing this, as I mentioned
before, to make this works really well,
you kind of want to turn on the auto run
mode so that it can write a test run
test by itself and try to fix the code.
It tries to create some test examples
from basic simple case to more
complicated nest example. And then it
write a function to actually convert the
string to proper JSON. And what happened
next is try to run the test here. And
here it is using the unit test. You can
see one out of five tests failed. Then
you go back to iterate code. Run the
test again. And this time it actually
failed more but it doesn't mean it is
passing. It just means it's discovering
new stuff. And while it is failing it is
also tried to debug it by adding some
debug lock so that if things failed it
will be able to better understand where
does things go wrong. A great now after
four or five different iterations all
five tests just passed and also write a
new example to test it. But this time it
find some vulnerability inside the code
where certain nested JSON string is not
passed properly. So it go back to fix
code more.
Great. So this example of how can you
use taskdriven development method to
build those much more complicated
function with lots of edge cases. And
now I want to convert this into a simple
web app that I can use. After a few
iterations, this website looks pretty
good. I can paste in any Python object
type string and it will automatically
convert into a trace structure like
this. And what I want to showcase next
is this concept called memory bank. It
is concept introduced by clean
initially. If you don't know claim, it
is a open-source cursor alternative
basically where you can just bring your
own API key and it work as a VS code
extension. What they introduce here is a
concept. What if the AI coding agents
can have memory of what has been done,
what type of text that choice we have
make as well as the latest task it is
working on. Then next time you ask
coding agent to build some new features,
it can read from this memory bank files
first to almost get a download about
what this project is, what has been
done, what kind of implementation
decision has been made to get enough
context so I can build new features on
top of what you have instead of messing
up your existing files. And to achieve
that it is actually nothing magic. They
come up with this system where they
define a few files to store different
type of context from project brief dog
which should define the core
requirements and goals and product
context which including the user
experience and how it should work and
active context should contain the
current work focus the recently changed
the active decisions and considerations
and important pattern and preference
where system patterns will store the
system architect key technical decisions
and tech context including the tech
stack as well as constraints and
dependencies and progress MD include
what works what's left to and they will
have a almost like cursor rules or
custom instruction to teach AI coding
agent about how to use those files and
when to use those files. And what's
really cool is that it not only works
for a new project that use from scratch.
You can also use the same method on your
existing project as well to ask AI
coding agent to look at your project
file, understand what's going on and
generate those files so that it has
context then developing new features and
I'm going to quickly show you how it
works in client initially and how can
you adopt same method in cursor with a
recent custom mode feature. Let's
firstly try out client. If you haven't
installed client yet, you can download
client which basically work as a VS code
extension. And what you need to do is
you will need to click on the settings
button where you need to copy this
prompt and add in here as a custom
instructions and click done. And then in
the project folder, create a new folder
called memory bank. Then there's a few
commands you can use. At the beginning,
you can say initialize memory bank which
will start by setting up all those
files. We force client to read the
memory bank files and continue where you
left off. and update memory bank is
something you can do after client finish
certain tasks. So I'll give prompt try
to understand the current project we
already set up and initiate memory bank.
You can see try to view what's inside
memory bank folder which should be
empty. Then decide to read the readme
and then try to read page by page. Then
firstly create this project brief file
which should contain the core
requirements. And here you can see that
it actually capture the core
requirements very clearly. So I save
this and then continue to create the
project context file which including
more detailed user experience
requirements. Then it also created a
system pattern which including the whole
architecture and data flow as well as
the key components. Then in the tech
context it articulate the whole tech
stack dependencies file structure as
well as implementation details that we
have done so far. And in active context
it summarize what has been done and what
are the next steps and progress will
list out the detailed tasks kind of
similar to taskmaster and we can
probably update prompt a little bit to
making sure it works with taskmaster as
well. And once it's finished in the
memory bank, you can see all the key
information about where we are with this
project has been stored here. Now let's
start the real interesting part. I will
start a new task and I won't give too
much context. Just give a prompt
implement a search function. And here
what I expected to do is to add a search
function to this JSON output viewer. So
I can search for the specific data point
and because of custom instruction before
you start implementing it will actually
look at the project brief doc to
understand the project that we already
set up and we're continuously looking
through multiple different docs to get
the full picture. Then it decide to read
the relevant files to get more context
and understanding the specific part that
you need to change. Then start making
change to the JSON display component and
adding the new search function. Then it
try to add new features to highlight the
search results. And after it finish,
it'll also go back to active context to
keep track that they just added search
functionality as well as a progress
file. And now if I go back to my
application, I can see a search function
here. It is fully functional. I can
search for anything and it'll
automatically highlight text which is
awesome. And most amazing part is that
it is system that continuously updating
this memory bank. So I can continue pile
up more and more complex feature in the
existing project without worrying it
messing up my project. And to get this
memory bank works in other EID like
cursor is also pretty straightforward.
There's a cursor memory bank rules
already written follow similar structure
where you can just click on row and copy
the whole thing go back to cursor where
they introduced this custom mode feature
recently. So you can literally come here
give a name and in the advanc option you
can just paste in this custom mode here
and that's it. You can choose this one
and then tell initiate memory bank. This
should actually start working and
setting up the memory bank for your
project out of box. Apart from this
basic setup, there's one project that I
thought is super interesting called
cursor memory bank. It basically took
what client has but pushed it a lot
further. It has few different modes. One
is van mode to to do the initial setup.
Plan mode to actually do the task
planning. Consider that like a engineer
manager and creative mode. So this is
interesting one. It's basically a mode
that specifically designed for syncing
and exploration. So it can be used for
you to discuss back and forth which text
stack you should go and you can also use
this for debug. So if you got a bug that
cursor just kind of getting stuck in the
loop, you can actually use creative mode
to ask it to figure out what are three
or four potential root cause. Try to
sync and play out and figure out which
is most likely one and then a building
mode to actually build out functionality
and it create a whole bunch of cursor
rules that will be dynamically retrieved
based on specific mode that they are in.
So this setup is a lot more
sophisticated but it's really really
interesting. I'm going to quickly show
you how can you use that. So to use this
new memory bank I can for example set up
a new nextjs project and cursor my app
and then I can get clone this project so
that it should download this folder and
this folder contain a lot of different
things but the actual thing you need is
this cursor rules so I'm going to drag
it to top level so I get this list of
cursor rules which I like dive a bit
deeper into but another thing is that
you have those custom instructions for
different modes I basically copy the
custom instruction here and then create
different custom modes in cursor the
first one can be van so van is basically
mode that will try to initialize the
memory bank. So I can paste in the whole
thing and then I will create another
custom mode called like plan paste the
specific custom instructions and same
thing for created mode and build mode.
So now we have four different modes that
can be used here. What I would do is
that I will click on van as I mentioned
before the rest of thing you actually
don't need. You can just delete it and
next we can start initialize the project
and set up as memory bank. If you're
already part of the AI builder club that
I'm building, then you can use tools
like 10X coder where it can help you
flesh out detailed PRD and requirements
of the project that you try to build
including project structure database
schema which you can use to copy paste
into prompt as context for this project.
I have put the link of AI builder club
in the description below so you can
click and join. But for this purpose,
I'm just going to prompt it here
directly with a simple to-do app. Zip
prompt van. I want to build a to-do app
with Nex.js and I already set up per.
Let's first initialize the memory bank.
So now it will start doing a few things.
You could see that here it load a few
different rules and this is the part
that became really interesting. If I go
inside cursor it has a whole bunch of
different rules. The first rule is this
me mode map. So this is like the
detailed instruction and a prompt about
what kind of process it should follow
and cursor also introduces type of new
root types which you can control and
decide when a rule should be attached.
First it will check this van mode map
and when you look inside this vam mode
map what it really does is that it kind
of instruct what are things you should
do to analyze the existing project. For
example, here it will firstly asked to
detect which platform it is using, which
OS it is using, the file path, the
command line it is needed as well as
platform checkpoint. And for each one,
it is actually leads to more specific
cursor rules like for platform detection
it will have specific rules about decide
whether it's using Windows, Mac or Linux
which probably leads to different
command line and file verification is a
rule that would tell the cursor those
are the best practice steps that you
should follow to understand existing
purchase. There are also something
called complexity determination. This is
a part where it will analyze the
complexity. So if it is simple
complexity like level one complexity, it
doesn't need to switch mode. It will
just continue doing the building in the
same mode. But if for something more
complicated like level two to level
four, it'll have more rules that will be
loaded dynamically. This is like super
interesting part. As you can see, this
is giant rules has been built out and
all those rules are kind of dynamically
feeding to the cursor agent. So with
this one it basically try to set up a
few files. One is a project brief to
understand the goal of the project the
tech context including what are the text
st it should be using or already used
the system patterns and active context
and in the end it gave me the conclusion
that this project classifies level two
complexities which means should actually
require plan mode breaking down task
into smaller ones. So now let's try it.
I will switch the mode here plan mode
and accept previous trends. So as it
enter the plan mode, it will start
loading a few other rules dynamically
and checking out the implementation plan
that has been written before and making
updates and now I can accept that. So it
updates the implementation plan and
breaking down task into more smaller and
modular one. And now I have a few
options. I can either go to creative
mode if I want to let's say understand
the trade-off between using Nex.js
versus view. Uh I can like just switch
to creative mode and bounce idea with
it. But I can also just click on build
mode to start boot. So I'm going to
start change to build mode and say
implement. During the implementation as
you can see it will again load those
rules dynamically. And this is probably
one of the most interesting part of this
project is that it kind of really try to
push the boundary and experiment how can
you use this custom rules as well as
custom modes together to create really
dynamic experience. I will just set up
this build mode to auto run. Why not?
Cool. So it build this app and I can
just add to-d do easily buy food have
dinner and actually build a bit more
feature than what you normally get with
my shot. There's tabs for filtering and
uh I can editing things with some
shortcuts can delete things. So so it's
kind of fully functional which is really
really cool and as a building things out
it also going back to file and making
updates. So the next time when I open a
even a new chat it will still have a
context about what has been done before
instead of starting from scratch and
messing things up. But what's really
interesting is that I can actually
delete this memory bank and because of
all those cursor rules it has it can
work with any existing purges as well by
looking through the whole project and
generate a memory bank about what this
existing project is about. For example,
let's try this. So I delete this
existing memory bank that I created
before. I will switch to VMO. I already
set up a to-do app in XJS. Let's
initialize a memory bank so I got
context about what has been done. So you
can see that it again raise those random
rules. Then it will start reading
through all the different files and
project structure based on best practice
rules that it was given and start
articulating what are the tax stack what
has been done into the memory bank. So
this is probably the most interesting
and useful part that it shows a
potential pathway to use cursor for your
existing project which is normally the
hardest part. This context will give so
much better starting point when you want
a cursor to implement new features. And
just as a quick example let's say I want
to add some new features. Each task can
be set due date, priority as well as
rich text for description. Now it will
make a plan about what are the core
features. Let's get into the build mode.
Let's add those new
features. Okay, so now I got this arrow
that it tried to resolve a few times but
just can't resolve it. This is where I
think creative mode will be interesting.
I can paste this in. I still get this
arrow. Help me debug please. and created
mode supposed to like sync through a few
potential options before it actually
take actions. So it's more likely to
solve the actual arrow instead of
stucking in this kind of loop. And now
if I switch to the app and click add it.
Great. Now it's working. It doesn't have
any arrows. So this is a quick example
of how you can use memory bank to either
new pure or existing purge. It's still
pretty early stage but I can already see
it improve the performance a lot. If you
want to get a prompt and cursor that
showcasing this video, you can join AI
builder club I'm building where I share
step-by-step process of my best practice
AI coding workflow as well as building
production ready agents and you can also
access platform like 10xcoder.dev dev
where it will help you build and
generate PRD that can instruct cursor
much better as well as next.js J boy
play they already have authentication
payment superbase setup so you can
launch your own SAS in just a weekend
but most importantly we have this
growing community of top AI builders who
are launching their AI product so if you
have any questions or doubts you can
just come here and make a post where I
and other community member can just come
and share our learnings. I have put the
link in the description below so you can
click and join. I hope you enjoyed this
video. Thank you and I see you next